David Wickes

I'm a web developer. I enjoy making things happen with a computer - mostly on the internet.

My Code

(see more on my GitHub)

Map To The Future	Battleships	Chitter
The final project at Makers Academy, we worked in a team of four to create an interactive timeline and a map to help visualize historical data and the connections and confluence of events. Lots of JS, and lots of maps!	Battleships, written in Ruby, tested with Rspec and played in the command line. Recently updated with a fork to initialize a board across multiple dimensions.	A Twitter clone created using Sinatra with features specced in Cucumber and unit tests in Rspec. The style of the HTML and CSS was heavily influenced by Yo.

Why I am a Developer

This year I decided to pursue a career in development after a lifetime of interest in computers and technology. I spent the first half of the year learning from home using online courses such as codecademy, Code School and Ruby Monk. I then joined Makers Academy in August to accelerate and fully embed my learning.

Makers Academy (August 2014 - October 2014)

- 12-week coding bootcamp
- Full-stack web development in Ruby, Rails, Sinatra and Node
- Learned TDD/BDD best practices, pair programming and other Agile techniques

Skills

- Agile values, principles and practice
- Basic design in Photoshop and InDesign
- · CSS3 and Sass
- Deploying to Heroku
- · Documenting in Markdown
- FactoryGirl
- · Feature tests in Cucumber
- HTML5, ERB, Haml, EJS and Jade
- Integration of APIs including Twilio, Stripe, Paperclip, and Mailgun
- Integration tests in Capybara with Phantom.js
- Integration tests in Mocha using the Chai assertion library
- JavaScript and CoffeeScript
- jQuery with Ajax techniques
- MongoDB with Mongoose
- Node.js with Express
- Object-oriented programming principles, including SOLID
- Pair programming
- PostgreSQL with ActiveRecord and DataMapper
- Ruby 2.1
- Ruby on Rails
- Sinatra
- Software design patterns
- Test & Behaviour Driven Development
- Twitter Bootstrap

- Unit testing with RSpec and Jasmine
- User authentication and authorisation with bcrypt and Devise
- · Version control with git and Github
- Vim
- Websockets

Employment

Liberis

Marketing Executive - (March 2014 - August 2014) - Designing and delivering responsive HTML emails in a test and learn program - Led integration of company data sources into Saleforce CRM - Started a project to place company telephony into the cloud - Temporary contract extended as a recognition of performance

Polyglobe Group

Marketing Executive - (March 2013 - February 2014) - Joined just prior to launch of new website to advise on SEO and create copy - Worked closely with developer to fix post-launch bugs and problems - Responsible for email marketing

The Kids Window

Web Master - (September 2009 - February 2013) - Joined small family-run website as a copywriter - Used HTML and CSS in creating marketing emails and landing pages - Developed a pricing algorithm implemented in Excel and Access

Norfolk Library Service

Library Assistant - (June 2005 - June 2009) - Worked as a library assistant in busy rural libraries - Drove a mobile library van :smile: - Helped almost everyone with the computers at some point

Education

Dates	Institution	Subject(s)
2003 - 2005	University of Warwick	MA Continental Philosophy
2000 - 2003	University of Warwick	BA Philosophy (1:1)
1991 - 1998	Wisbech Grammar School	A level Maths, Biology Chemistry; 10 GCSEs

I Like

Parsing natural language, writing in markdown, playing with Vim, semantically beautiful code, playing chess, calligraphy, typography, Kant, Nietzsche, Wittgenstein and walking my dog, Erik.

Say Hi

You can reach me as @gypsydave5 on Twitter and dave@gypsydave5.com. There's even a blog - blog.gypsydave5.com - if you'd like to see what I'm up to and thinking.